# Ben Osborne

Experienced full stack software engineer with proven record of implementing real business solutions.

- location: Oconomowoc, Wisconsin
- phone: 414-534-4731
- email: ben@osbornesupremacy.com
- linkedin: linkedin.com/in/benosborne
- github: github.com/osbornesupremacy
- stackoverflow: stackoverflow.com/users/4117922

## About Me

I am an experienced software engineer, passionate about building solutions that create value for organizations.

In my career I've worked as a software developer, development team lead, and application development manager. In my current role as an software architect, I provide designs, prototypes, patterns, standards, and mentoring for my team members and organization.

I am most experienced with the Microsoft ecosystem, particularly .NET (Core and Framework) web and Windows applications with SQL Server databases. Additionally, I enjoy learning new technologies as needs and opportunities arise.

I enjoy practicing and advocating for SOLID design principles, as well as DevOps disciplines.

## **Proficiencies**

### **Highly Proficient**

- .NET (Framework–.NET 6) Web Applications (Web API / MVC / Webforms), Windows Services, console applications, mainly with C#.
  - o Libraries AutoMapper, Dapper, EntityFramework, Serilog, AutoFac, Swagger, Json.NET
  - Testing Libraries Moq, AutoFixture, Bogus, AutoBogus, FluentAssertions, FluentValidation, xUnit
- SQL Server (2000—2019) Stored procedures, functions, windowing, table-value parameters, indexing

## **Moderately Proficient**

- Azure App Services, SQL Databases, CosmosDb, Application Insights, KeyVault, Function Apps
- AWS Lambda, Transfer, S3, Workspaces
- Web Frontend Blazor, TypeScript, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery
- CI/CD GitHub Actions, Azure DevOps
- Misc. PowerShell, Docker (Compose), Twilio (Studio, Function Services, Flex)

### Just Enough To Be Dangerous

- gRPC Demo available at github.com/ben-osborne-intelliscript/Getting-Started-With-Grpc-Net
- Web Frontend Angular, Hugo
- Misc. SpecFlow, Nginx, R

### **Currently Learning**

- In Progress RabbitMQ
- Future F#

## Reading List

- In Progress Release It!
- Recently Finished Domain Driven Design, The DevOps Handbook, The Unicorn Project, Beyond the Phoenix Project
- All-time Favorites The Phoenix Project, The Goal, Atomic Habits, Essentialism

# **Employment History**

Milliman IntelliScript (2017-05—Present)

#### **Software Architect** (2020-11—Present)

- Helped design and implement architecture for backend API (.NET Core 3.1), which was part of a complete UI rewrite of organization's flagship web application.
- Created code and architectural standards for backend development team.
- Designed and implemented prototype applications for processing health data (HL7 standards).

## Software Development Team Lead (2019-09—2020-10), Software Developer (2017-05—2019-08)

- Developed windows microservices to facilitate data integrations with multiple vendors, and subsequent processing of that data.
- Developed and deployed mock web APIs to Azure to help develop and test our API consumption services.
- Led the effort to adopt unit testing, creating patterns and standards for the team.

## Sand Castle Field Services, LLC (2014-10—2017-05)

#### Senior Application Developer (2014-10—2017-05)

- Full stack ASP.NET development and support
- Created new Intranet built on .NET Framework MVC, training other developers on that methodology.
- Created modules for invoice dispute resolution, recruiting, licensing, phone call / SMS automation, code violation tracking.
- Established automated functionality testing for web applications using Selenium.
- Established Continuous Integration
- Transitioned codebase from SourceSafe to Team Foundation System. Implemented source control for SQL Server DBs.

#### The Benefit Services Group, Inc. (1999-07—2014-10)

### **Application Development Manager** (2012-06—2014-10)

- Managed a team of ASP.NET / SQL Server developers, responsible for developing, implementing, and supporting a variety of ASP.NET web applications and data integrations.
- Standardized career path, job titles, job descriptions, and salary range for development team.
- Worked directly with customers to design and implement integrations and modules to facilitate online benefits enrollment and reporting.

#### **Software Developer** (1999-07—2012-05)

- Key member of the team responsible for developing, improving, and supporting organization's flagship product, an online group benefits enrollment web application.
- Helped the system mature, developing patterns and integrations with dozens of vendors (e.g. medical, dental, vision, life, and flexible spending account administrators, HRIS systems, payroll systems, etc.)

# Education

# University of Wisconsin—Milwaukee

- B.A., Philosophy
  - o Graduated cum laude, 2000
- Political Science minor

## Milwaukee School of Engineering

• Attended from 1995—1996